I recognized the roles that were placed on me very early. One persistent concept that I observed -- existing in our language, in our media -- was that women are not only supposed to have children, they are supposed to want to. This existed everywhere. It existed in the ways that adults spoke to me when they posed questions in the context of "when." "When you get married ..." "When you have kids ..." And these future musings were always presented to me like part of this American dream, but it always felt to me like someone else's dream. You see, a value that I have always understood about myself was that I never wanted children. And as a kid, when I would try to explain this, this disconnect between their roles and my values, they often laughed in the way that adults do at the absurdities of children. And they would tell me knowingly, "You'll change your mind." And people have been saying things like that to me my whole life. Otherwise polite conversation can turn intrusive fast. "Does your husband know?" (Laughter) "Do your parents know?" "Don't you want a family?" "Don't you want to leave anything behind?" And the primary buzzword when discussing childlessness, "That's selfish." There are countless reasons a woman may have for choosing to abstain from motherhood, the majority of them not self-prioritizing. But it is still socially acceptable to publicly vilify women as such, because none of these reasons have made it into the social narrative. When I was little and learning about the inevitability of maternity, it was never explained to me the commonness of these factors that women consider, like the risk of passing on hereditary illness, the danger of having to stop life-saving medication for the duration of your pregnancy, concern about overpopulation, your access to resources, and the fact that there are 415,000 children in the foster-care system in the United States at any given time. Reasons like these, many more, and the fact that I don't like to leave things of this magnitude to chance, all informed my decision to become surgically sterilized. I began my research eagerly. I wanted to fully understand all that was going to come with undergoing a tubal ligation, which is just another word for getting your tubes tied. I wanted to know approval to aftermath, satisfaction rates, risks, statistics. And at first, I was empowered. You see, the way the narrative has always been taught to me, I would have thought that women who didn't want children were so rare, and then I learned one in five American women won't be having a biological child -- some by choice, some by chance. (Applause) But I was not alone. But the more I read, the more disheartened I became. I read women's stories, trying desperately to get this procedure. I learned how common it was for women to exhaust their finances appealing to dozens of ob-gyns over many years, only to be turned down so many times, often with such blatant disrespect that they just gave up. Women reported that medical practitioners were often condescending and dismissive of their motivations, being told things like, "Come back when you're married with a child." But women who did have children, who went to go get this procedure, were told they were too young, or they didn't have enough children, which is very interesting, because the legal requirements in my state for getting this kind of surgery were, "Be at least 21 years old," "appear of sound mind, acting of your own accord," and "have a 30-day waiting period." And I was perplexed that I could meet all of these legal requirements and still have to face a battle in the exam room for my bodily autonomy. And it was daunting, but I was determined. I remember I dressed so professionally to that first appointment. (Laughter) I sat up straight. I spoke clearly. I wanted to give that doctor every piece of evidence that I was not the date of birth in that file. And I made sure to mention things like, "I just got my bachelor's degree and I'm applying to these doctoral programs, I'm going to study these things." And "my long-term partner has this kind of business," and "I've done research on this for months. I understand everything about it, all the risks." Because I needed the doctor to know that this was not a whim, not reactionary, not your 20-something looking to go out and party without fear of getting knocked up ... (Laughter) that this supported something integral to who I was. And I understand informed consent, so I fully expected to be reeducated on how it all worked, but ... At one point, the information being given to me started to feel agenda'd, interlaced with bias and inflated statistics. The questions began to feel interrogative. At first they were asking me questions that seemed to understand my situation better, and then it seemed like they were asking questions to try to trip me up. I felt like I was on the witness stand, being cross-examined. The doctor asked me about my partner. "How does he or she feel about all of this?" "Well, I've been with the same man for five years, and he fully supports any decision I make for my body." And he said, "Well, what happens in the future, if you change partners? What happens when that person wants children?" And I didn't quite know how to react to that, because what I was hearing was this doctor tell me that I'm supposed to disregard everything I believe if a partner demands children. So I told him not to worry about that. My stance on childbearing has always been first date conversation. (Laughter) (Cheering) He then asks me to consider how "in 20 years, you could really come to regret this" ... as though I hadn't. I told him, "OK, if I wake up one day and realize, you know, I wish I'd made a different decision back then, the truth is, I'd only removed a single path to parenthood. I never needed biology to form family anyway." (Applause) And I would much rather deal with that any day than deal with one day waking up, realize I'd had a child that I didn't really want or was prepared to care for. Because one of these affects only me. The other affects a child, their development, their well-being -- (Applause) and human beings are not to be gambled with. He then tells me why no one was going to approve this procedure, certainly not he, because of a concept called medical paternalism, which allows him, as my well-informed provider,
Reconocí los roles que se me asignaron muy temprano. Un concepto persistente que observé que existe en nuestro idioma, en nuestros medios, era que las mujeres no solo deben tener hijos, se supone que los quieren. Existía en todas partes. Existía en la forma en que los adultos me hablaban cuando plantearon preguntas en el contexto de "cuándo". "Cuando te cases...". "Cuando tengas hijos...". Y estas reflexiones futuras siempre se me presentaron como parte de este sueño americano, pero siempre me pareció el sueño de otra persona. Ya ven, un valor que siempre he entendido sobre mí era que nunca querría tener hijos. Y cuando era niña, cuando trataba de explicabsn esto, esta desconexión entre sus roles y mis valores, a menudo se reían cómo lo hacen los adultos ante las cosas absurdas de los niños. Y ellos me dirían a sabiendas, "Cambiarás de opinión". Y la gente me ha estado diciendo cosas así toda mi vida. De lo contrario, una conversación educada puede convertirse en intrusión rápida. "¿Tu esposo lo sabe?". (Risas) "¿Tus padres lo saben?". "¿No quieres una familia?". "¿No quieres dejar nada atrás?". Y la palabra de moda principal al hablar de falta de hijos, "Eso es egoísta". Hay innumerables razones por las que una mujer puede tener que elegir abstenerse de la maternidad, la mayoría de ellas no se autoprioriza. Pero todavía es socialmente aceptable vilipendiar públicamente a tales mujeres, porque ninguna de estas razones ha llegado a la narrativa social. Cuando era pequeña y aprendí sobre la inevitabilidad de la maternidad, nunca me explicaron lo común de estos factores que las mujeres consideran, como el riesgo de transmitir enfermedades hereditarias, el peligro de tener que suspender los medicamentos que salvan sus vidas durante la duración de su embarazo, preocupación por la superpoblación, y el acceso a los recursos, y el hecho de que hay 415 000 niños en el sistema de cuidado de crianza en EE. UU. en cualquier momento dado. Razones como estas, muchas más, y el hecho de que no me gusta dejar cosas de esta magnitud al azar, todas formaron mi decisión para ser esterilizada quirúrgicamente. Comencé mi investigación con entusiasmo. Quería entender completamente todo lo que vendría al someterse a una ligadura de trompas, que es solo otra palabra para atar tus tubos. Quería saber de la aprobación después, índices de satisfacción, riesgos, estadísticas. Y al principio, fui empoderada. Ya ven, la forma en que la narración siempre se me ha enseñado, Pensé que las mujeres que no querían tener hijos eran tan raras, y luego aprendí que una de cada cinco mujeres estadounidenses no tendrá un hijo biológico algunas por elección, algunas por casualidad. (Aplausos) Pero no estaba sola. Pero cuanto más leo, más descorazonada me siento. Leo historias de mujeres, tratando desesperadamente de obtener este procedimiento. Aprendí lo común que era para las mujeres agotar sus finanzas apelando a docenas de ginecólogos durante muchos años, solo para ser rechazada tantas veces, a menudo con tanta falta de respeto que simplemente se dieron por vencidas. Las mujeres informaron que los médicos a menudo eran condescendientes y desdeñosos de sus motivaciones, que decían cosas como, "Vuelve cuando estés casada y tengas un hijo". Pero las mujeres que sí tuvieron hijos, que fueron a buscar este procedimiento, les dijeron que eran muy jóvenes, o no tenían suficientes hijos, lo que es muy interesante, porque los requisitos legales en mi estado para este tipo de cirugía eran, "Tener al menos 21 años de edad", "aparecer de buen juicio, actuar por cuenta propia" y "un período de espera de 30 días". Y estaba perpleja de poder cumplir con todos estos requisitos legales y aún tener que enfrentar una batalla en la sala de examen para mi autonomía corporal. Y fue desalentador, pero estaba decidida. Recuerdo que me vestí tan profesionalmente en esa primera cita. (Risas) Me senté derecha. Hablé claramente. Quería darle a ese doctor toda la evidencia de que yo no era la fecha de nacimiento en ese archivo. Y me aseguré de mencionar cosas como, "Acabo de obtener mi grado y estoy postulando a estos programas de doctorado, voy a estudiar estas cosas". Y "mi socio a largo plazo tiene este tipo de negocio" y "He investigado esto durante meses. Entiendo todo al respecto, todos los riesgos". Porque necesitaba que el médico supiera que esto no era un capricho, no era una reacción, no es sus 20-algo que busca salir y divertirse sin miedo a ser golpeada... (Risas) que estaba apoyaba en algo integral a lo que yo era. Y entiendo el consentimiento informado, así que esperaba ser reeducada sobre cómo funcionaba todo, pero... En un momento dado, la información que me fue dando me hizo sentir agendada, entrelazada con sesgo y estadísticas infladas. Las preguntas comenzaron a parecer interrogativas. Al principio me estaban haciendo preguntas que parecía buscar entender mejor mi situación, y luego parecía que estaban haciendo preguntas para tratar de confundirme. Me sentí como si estuviera en el estrado de los testigos, siendo interrogada. El doctor me preguntó acerca de mi compañero. "¿Cómo se siente él o ella acerca de todo esto?". "Bueno, he estado con el mismo hombre durante cinco años, y él apoya totalmente cualquier decisión que tome para mi cuerpo". Y él dijo: "Bueno, ¿qué pasa en el futuro, si cambias de pareja? ¿Qué sucederá cuando esa persona quiera hijos? No sabía muy bien cómo reaccionar a eso, porque lo que estaba escuchando era a este doctor decirme que se supone que debo ignorar todo lo que creo si un compañero demanda niños. Entonces le dije que no se preocupara por eso. Mi postura sobre la procreación siempre ha sido conversación de la primera cita. (Risas) (Aplausos) Luego me pide que considere cómo "en 20 años, realmente podría llegar a arrepentirte de esto"... como si no lo hubiera hecho. Le dije, "Bien, si me levanto un día y me doy cuenta, ya sabe, que desearía haber tomado una decisión distinta, la verdad es que solo habría eliminado un solo camino hacia la maternidad. Nunca necesité biología para formar familia de todos modos". (Aplausos) Y preferiría lidiar con eso cualquier día que lidiar con un día despertar, dándome cuenta de que tuve un hijo que realmente no quería o estaba preparada para cuidar. Porque uno de estos me afecta solo a mí. El otro afecta a un niño, su desarrollo, su bienestar... (Aplausos) y los seres humanos no deben ser una apuesta. Luego me dice por qué nadie iba a aprobar este procedimiento, ciertamente no él, debido a un concepto llamado paternalismo médico, lo que le permite, como mi proveedor bien informado,
to make decisions for me ... based on his perception of my best interest, regardless of what I, as the patient, want or believe. He takes this opportunity to step out and discuss my case with my potential surgeon, and through the door, I hear him describe me as a little girl. I was so offended. I wanted to defend myself. I wanted to explicitly explain to each one of these providers how they were treating me, that it was belittling and sexist, and I didn't have to take it. But I did take it. I swallowed every sharp word in my throat, clenched my jaw, and instead answered each one of their condescending questions and statements. I had come here looking for objectivity and support and instead I felt dismissed and silenced, and I hated myself for it. I hated that I was letting people disrespect me repeatedly. But this was my one shot. That was one of multiple consultations that I had to go to. At one point, I had seen five or six medical professionals in the same hour. The door to the exam room felt more like the door to a clown car. There's my primary, there's his colleague, the director, OK. It felt like I was asking them to infect me with smallpox instead of, I don't know, obtain birth control. But I didn't waver, and I was persistent, and I eventually convinced one of them to allow the procedure. And even as I am in the room, signing the consent forms and getting the hormone shots and tying up loose ends ... my doctor is shaking his head in disapproval. "You'll change your mind." I never really understood how strongly this society clings to this role until I went through this. I experienced firsthand, repeatedly, how people, be it medical providers, colleagues, strangers, were literally unable to separate me being a woman from me being a mother. And I've always believed that having children was an extension of womanhood, not the definition. I believe that a woman's value should never be determined by whether or not she has a child, because that strips her of her entire identity as an adult unto herself. Women have this amazing ability to create life, but when we say that that is her purpose, that says that her entire existence is a means to an end. It's so easy to forget the roles that society places on us are so much more than mere titles. What about the weight that comes with them, the pressure to conform to these standards ... the fear associated with questioning them, and the desires that we cast aside to accept them? There are many paths to happiness and fulfillment. They all look very different, but I believe that every one is paved with the right to self-determination. I want women to know that your choice to embrace or forego motherhood is not in any way tied to your worthiness or identity as spouses, as adults, or as women ... and there absolutely is a choice behind maternity, and it is yours and yours alone. Thank you. (Applause)
tomar decisiones por mí... basado en su percepción de mi mejor interés, independientemente de lo que yo, como paciente, desee o crea. Aprovecha esta oportunidad para salir y discutir mi caso con mi potencial cirujano, y a través de la puerta, escucho que me describe como una niña pequeña. Estaba tan ofendida. Yo quería defenderme. Quería explicar explícitamente a cada uno de estos proveedores cómo me estaban tratando, que era humillante y sexista, y no tuve que tomarlo. Pero lo tomé. Me tragué cada palabra aguda en mi garganta, apreté mi mandíbula, y en su lugar respondí cada una de sus preguntas y declaraciones condescendientes. Vine aquí buscando objetividad y apoyo y en cambio me sentí despedida y silenciada, y me odié a mí misma por eso. Odiaba que permitiera que la gente me faltara el respeto en repetidas ocasiones. Pero esta fue mi única oportunidad. Esa fue una de las múltiples consultas a las que tuve que acudir. En un momento dado, había visto a 5 o 6 profesionales médicos en la misma hora. La puerta de la sala de examen se parecía más a la puerta de un auto payaso. Ahí está mi primaria, está su colega, el director, bien. Sentí que les pedía que me contagiaran de viruela en lugar de, no sé, obtener anticonceptivos. Pero no vacilé, y fui persistente, y eventualmente convencí a uno de ellos de permitir el procedimiento. E incluso en la sala, firmando yo los formularios de consentimiento, recibiendo inyecciones de hormonas y atando cabos sueltos, mi doctor menea la cabeza en señal de desaprobación. "Cambiarás de opinión". Nunca entendí realmente con qué fuerza esta sociedad se aferra a este rol hasta que pasé por esto. Experimenté de primera mano, repetidamente, cómo las personas, ya sean proveedores médicos, colegas, extraños, fueron literalmente incapaces de verme siendo una mujer separada de verme como madre. Y siempre creí que tener hijos era una extensión de la feminidad, no la definición. Creo que el valor de una mujer nunca debe ser determinado por si tiene o no un hijo, porque eso la despoja de toda su identidad como adulta en sí misma. Las mujeres tienen esta increíble habilidad para crear vida, pero cuando decimos que ese es su propósito, eso dice que toda su existencia es un medio para un fin. Es muy fácil olvidar los roles que la sociedad nos impone son mucho más que meros títulos. ¿Qué pasa con el peso que viene con ellos? la presión de cumplir con estos estándares... el miedo asociado con cuestionarlos, y los deseos que desechamos para aceptarlos? Hay muchos caminos hacia la felicidad y la realización. Todos se ven muy diferentes, pero creo que cada uno está pavimentado con el derecho a la autodeterminación. Quiero que las mujeres sepan que su elección es aceptar o no la maternidad no está de ninguna manera atada a su dignidad o identidad como cónyuges, como adultas o como mujeres... y hay absolutamente una elección detrás de la maternidad, y es tuya y solo tuya. Gracias. (Aplausos)